Well, my friends, let's make a quick sort algorithm and see language.
So first of all, we start by including the studiato and making a function to swab the elements.
We have made this function many times in the previous videos, so we need a temporary element and a
variable tee that swaps the variable a two variable B and variable B to variable A.
And the first steps to bring in the temp, the value of a second step, a equal to B and B equal to
that the value.
Let's make it function to find the part the chin position.
We have talked about this algorithm in the previous videos that we need a partition method that start
partitioning that.
And a function that allow us to make that quick sort and call it recursively starting by left and right
by segmentation and sorting.
So for that, we start by making a function and that that does turn.
Its returning type is integer and called partition took into the parameters, the array that we are
going to partition that low and the high.
And this is that we are going to see, so select the rightmost element as before, so we get that pivot
equal to the array, equal to high.
So the last element the great, the rightmost element aspect, the pointer for the greater element are
entirely equal to low minus one.
Now traverse each element of the array, compare to them with their pivot.
So for that, we need to make an early and a loop before glue that starts from equal to low and stops
at less than the high and go through all the element by G Plus Plus.
If the array at index is less than or equal to the pivot, then make the smaller pivot is found so it
with a greater element pointed by AI and we increase it by plus +1.
Now swap element at eye with the element at J swapping here at the end of array at index AI and Array
at Index J then swept the pivot element with the greater element at AI.
We make again swab.
We call them functions where we swept the array index at the Element at Array Index AI +1 with array
at index high.
So we are switching and swapping the pivot element with that greater element at high and return the
part the chimp point i +1.
This is the watch the chin function.
We make the.
Second, function that we will use that is quick sort, this sort will trigger that partition method
that we have created.
And when it is used.
So also, it took into the parameters that they that we are going to sort that low and the high, if
low less than high, then find the pivot elements such that the elements greater than pivot are on the
left of pivot and elements greater.
Then pivot are on the right of the front.
OK.
And create an integer called PI equal to part the chin.
This is the usage of the part, the function that we have created called part the chin.
We passed the array and the low and high.
So these are the parameters that we are going to do, pass them into the main function that later we
will create recursive call of the left of the pivot.
We said that in the previous video that we need to use recursion two times and divide and conquer this.
That quick sort is one of the divide and conquer algorithms.
So divide and conquer algorithm is based on research.
And here as the usage of the recursion.
So we are going to call that quick sword with the array past.
And here we passed the element there at the perimeter low.
OK, at the first step, we start by look at five months and the second step we call also the recursive
call on the right of the pivot.
But here we have passed that high.
This will allow us to make a quick sorting for the left substrate.
This is the array and this will ensure that all the elements of the left substrate are sorted and they
are segmented into elements, single elements.
So.
That goal and the target of the quick sword algorithm.
Is to reach and serve them according.
Accordingly and use and and reaches a step where we have single elements.
So for that, we have made this for the left the first time and the second step.
We start by making recursively and passing the high and right of privacy.
So we also made this for the right, so we need to get the right elements are segmented into single
elements and they are.
Sort, this is that, Richard.
This is the usage of recursion in this way.
No, the function to print the elements of the array, we have talked about it many times, starting
from zero and less than size.
And then we will create and print the element at today and.
Main function, we will create a function called data.
Sorry, not function, it's the main function, and here is an array data that we are going to sort,
and we will start by making an and is created by the size of data.
This is really over the size of data at Index Z.
OK.
This is the way that how we can get the size of the array and see.
Now printing unsorted array, we print the array that it is not sorted, so we will get this.
And after that, we perform a quick search on the data, so we called the method the quick sort.
This is the quick sort and we pass the array data.
We start from zero.
This is the low and the index, and minus one is the high, which is the last element of that data,
which is the last index, the element of that.
Now, in order to print that, a certain array in an ascending order print data and and this is the
size and this is the thing.
OK.
This is the quick sort algorithm, we have implemented it in sea correctly.
And they want from you to write this code in your C compiler and test it and play with with the codes
and see the functionality of how to if we if we need to make it ascending or descending order.
If I pass the right without the high and high, without the low.
So, so please, please, guys.
Write this and your compiler and try to to make everything by your own and write them down because they
are very important.
And these that these questions are asked in the university and in and the inverse the.